Ng'etich Sila Kiptoo

62014-0100, Nairobi

www.linkedin.com/in/sila-ng-etich-39a9a3164

Youth advocate and professional IT specialist committed to steering youth empowerment programs through collaboration with both government and non-government projects. Involved in youth mentorship on digital opportunities and online work.

Currently working with eMobilis Mobile Training Institute in operationalizing AJIRA Youth Empowerment Center in Nairobi. The AJIRA Digital program is aimed at enabling youth to access and earn a decent wage from online work opportunities.

Work Experience

EMobilis Mobile

Technology Institute

April 2020-Date

Center Manager (Ajira Digital)

Duties and Responsibilities

- Drive program values and philosophy through all activities at the Center
- Ensure timely Opening and Closing of the Center for youth to access Programs, Trainings daily.
- Safeguard, protect and maintain (Level 1 basic support) the Center infrastructure and Equipment.
- Coordinate and oversee the Weekly & Monthly schedules for the Training activities with Trainers.
- Provide timely and detailed Weekly Reports on Trainings, activities, events, incidents at the Center.
- Oversee the development and roll out of the Training Calendar in the Center.
- Manage resources, including working with the Ministry of ICT and the MP's Office, vendors and collaborators to deliver the Center activities.
- Coordinate logistics, planning, management and execution for the Trainings and other Center Activities.
- Effectively communicate with team members, trainers and management.
- ❖ Coordinate the Trainers and supervise any administrative staff.
- Oversee the marketing + promotion of Center activities for youth to benefit from the Center.
- Coordinate Mobilization efforts in the Community by publicizing activities and upcoming training.
- Develop and implement activities within the budget provided by Management.

NG'ETICH SILA Page | 2

- Build and maintain relationships with collaborating partner organizations including Community organizations.
- Build a Database of interested participants in an effort to create a pool for Center activities.
- ❖ Co-ordinate success stories, social media engagement and oversee the capturing of session photos/videos.
- Supervise and work with Trainers on gathering of data, sign-up sheets and issuance of certificates to Trainees
- Oversee Quality Assurance of the programs run through suggesting areas for improvement etc.
- Evaluate Center performance to ensure that trainings at the Center are meeting the needs of the learners and improving performance of the organization.
- Mentor and support youth in the community to benefit from Online Work- Champion Online Work

Milimani Law Courts

July 2019-July 2020

ICT Directorate Intern

Duties and Responsibilities

- Provide general technical support to users and staff
- Responding to helpdesk tickets within the OS ticketing and Cisco phones.
- Troubleshooting and regular inspection of printers, routers, switches, CCTV Cameras, access points, and computer hardware.
- Giving personalized guidance and support to staff on computer-related issues.
- ❖ Providing audio-visual equipment to courts for evidence projection.
- Performing regular checkups, maintenance, and allocation of network cables.
- Performing software updates and installation to devices.
- Allocation, distribution, and assigning of new devices to staff through the assets management system.
- Performing basic configurations on network devices such as routers, switches, and access points.
- Maintaining stable internet connectivity.
- Installation of antivirus.
- Uploading and tagging new old devices on the assets management system.
- Perform any other role that arises in matters ICT.

NG'ETICH SILA Page | 3

Kapsabet Nandi Water and Sanitation Company.

16th June-1st August 2017

ICT Intern

Duties and Responsibilities

- Planning for upgrades and software changes to increase efficiency.
- Servicing of all the ICT equipment
- Doing data backup in the water billing software.
- Troubleshooting computers in the remote stations.
- ❖ Training users on how water billing is done in the company.
- Conducting a Geographical Information System (GIS) mapping on the PDQs to capture the location of all meters.
- Installation and setting up of new access points
- Setting up the office LAN and WAN.
- Simple office network management including troubleshooting and responding to support requests.

Siary Cyber Café (Founder & Director)

- ♦ Help customers with the use of computers and applications.
- Responding to customers who encounter error messages from accessing sites, emailing, or downloading content.
- Troubleshooting, hardware, terminals, software, and connectivity issues.
- Track customers' time at computer terminals.
- ♦ Monitor use of computers to ensure compliance with café' policies and applicable laws and policies.
- Resolving technical problems with the design and the delivery of internet services and processing problems of the users.
- Performing minor repairs and getting replaced faulty computers and peripherals.

Study Bay 2015 – 2021

- Research Writer- thesis, dissertations, and course assignments.
- Doing course projects
- Researching industry-related topics (combining online sources, interviews, and studies)
- Editing, adapting, and rewriting articles, research papers.

Uvocorp 2022-Date

Freelance Writer (Resume writing, technical writing and proposals)

NG'ETICH SILA Page | 4

Education and Certifications

Kenya Technical Trainers College April 2019 –December 2021	Advanced Diploma in Technical Teacher Education
Google (Coursera Course)	Agile Project Management
Microsoft July 1, 2020	Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
Kenya Education Network Feb 14, 2020	Cybersecurity Course Awareness
Internet Society September 9 th -October 13 th 2019	Introduction to Network Operations:UNIX/Linux and Configuring DNS
eMobilis Mobile Training Institute 17 TH August	Basic Digital Skills Training
Huawei 5 TH -18 TH November 2019	Huawei Certified Intermediate Associate (Security)
Huawei 15 TH - 29TH August 2019	Huawei Certified Intermediate Associate (Routing and Switching)
University of Eldoret 2013 – 2017	Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (IT) Second Class Honors (Upper Division)
Terige Secondary School 2009 - 2012	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

NG'ETICH SILA Page | 5

Roxy School

2007-2008

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

Software Packages

Microsoft Office Suite

Sublime Text 3 PHPMyAdmin

- ❖ Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft OneNote, Adobe PageMaker, and Microsoft Outlook.
- Snippets
- ❖ CSV, SQL and XML

Libraries and Frameworks

C#-.NET Framework 4.5

Bootstrap 3

CSS-Preprocessor

HTML 5

Hobbies and Interests

- Traveling
- Networking and Socializing
- Writing (Scholarly and academic papers).
- Watching documentaries
- Playing football.

Referees

Miss. Immaculate Mutinda

Assistant Program Manager

EMobilis Mobile Training Institute.

P.0 BOX 939-00606 Nairobi

Phone No. 0716392615

Email: immaculate.mutinda@emobilis.org

Miss. Yvonne Mbae

Head of Support Services

Milimani Law Courts.

P.O BOX 30041-00100 Nairobi

Phone No: 0710777080

Email: yvonne.mbae@court.go.ke

Mr. Edwin Kittur

ICT Officer

Kapsabet Nandi Sanitation Company.

i Water

and

P.O BOX 970-30300.

Phone No: 0724075746

Email: edcollans@gmail.com